Oh no, more leaves!
Cleaning up tomorrow morning is going to be difficult.
I'll bet that's difficult too.
Huh?
Miss Sayaka...
Is there nothing I can do?
Kobato!
Welcome back!
I'm home!
Did you all go out together?
Yes. You see, their school had a bazaar today.
Bazaar?
It's where everyone brings all sorts of things,
and sells them for the sake of the school!
Oh...
That's it!
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday,
your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...Mysterious Lifeform.
Bazaar!
Miss Sayaka, let's have a bazaar!
What?
Let's sell a ton of stuff and pay back the debt collector!
Kobato...
If we pay back the loan, we won't be
evicted and everything will be okay, right?
Accounts
Right?
Let's do it, let's have a bazaar!
Kobato, you see—
If the loan was something that
could've been paid off that easily,
it would've been taken care of a long time ago!
Fujimoto...
You do something like that at a big school,
not a little nursery with only a few students.
We wouldn't get that much money.
So doing that here would be pointless.
I'm sorry for causing such a fuss...
I'll go clean up outside, okay?
To be all enthusiastic and go all out holding a bazaar is just like her...
But when things don't work out, she'll be upset too.
So I understand your desire to make her give up that idea,
but you shouldn't put it like that.
If you're too brusque about
things, it'll look like you're bullying.
I...
I got all worked up by myself...
Both Fujimoto and Miss Sayaka were shocked, weren't they?
I'm such an idiot, aren't I...
Well, I suppose you are.
But I don't think it's bad to be so determined.
Ioryogi!
D-Don't hug me! You—!
Kobato.
Miss Sayaka...
Let's do it. Let's have a bazaar!
Huh?
Bazaar?
It's where you bring in no longer needed or handmade things from home and sell them.
It's like playing store!
I want to be in charge of the yakisoba stand!
That's a good idea too.
I've written down the details in your correspondence books.
Make sure you show your folks at home, okay?
Okay!
Let's do our best! Yay!
Fujimoto.
It's good that Kobato's happy again, isn't it?
I couldn't care less.
Bye bye!
Miss Sayaka, see you tomorrow!
See you tomorrow, goodbye!
Bazaar!
What is that?
Mr. Doggy!
And that one?
Miss Kitty!
Don't you feel bad for the cat and the dog?
He got you there. That's why you have no answer, huh?
Thank you for your hard work!
Thank you!
Did you draw this, Kobato?
Yes!
You're good at this, aren't you!
Really! What an adorable duck
and sheep you have drawn here!
Then, I'll be excusing myself first.
Do you have work?
Yes.
Don't push yourself too hard, okay?
I'm not.
Miss Sayaka, you too. Don't push yourself too hard.
So that's what Fujimoto
looks like when he smiles...
Mysterious
Lifeform
Then if you'll excuse me.
How childish of him.
He must've taken a liking to you, Kobato.
What?!
Seriously.
It's impossible for both Fujimoto and that other guy to just be straightforward about things.
The other guy?
Oh! Ah, thank you for your work today, Kobato.
Let's continue preparing for the bazaar tomorrow.
Do you think she was talking about her husband?
If I remember correctly, you ordered a birthday cake for your husband here before, right?
Right...
Could be I guess.
I wonder what she meant when she said that it's impossible for him to just be straightforward.
I wonder.
It's a mystery.
Less of a mystery than your pictures, Dobato.
That's mean!
Everyone, thank you all so much!
Huh?
What is this?
A weather fortune doll!
Weather fortune doll?
You make it and hang it up and wish for good weather!
I wonder who brought them.
Did you make them, Naomi?
Yeah...
The weather fortune dolls I made... they bring a lot of sunny days.
Field trip days and pool days are always sunny.
What amazing weather fortune dolls!
I wonder if they'll sell...
They will!
I also made something to sell. Let's line them up and sell them together!
Yeah!
All right then, let's put price tags on the things you all brought in today!
Here you go.
Kobato.
What is it?
The nursery won't close if we sell a lot of weather fortune dolls, right?
Yes, don't worry!
You know... my mommy...
She's going to have a baby soon!
Really?
Congratulations!
So you see...
Mommy's going to take off from work starting this month,
but once the baby gets a little older, she says she'll go back again.
She says that she wants to leave the baby in the care of Yomogi Nursery again!
And since I'm the big sister, I'm going to come and pick the baby up from the Nursery!
I'll be able to see you and Miss Sayaka everyday!
I want to see you as a big sister everyday too!
Everyone, let's do our best!
Yeah!
Yomogi Nursery Bazaar
European Style Sweets   Tirol
It's gotten really late.
Do you work at Yomogi Nursery?
Y-Yes...
That voice... You're the girl who picked up the phone last time?
You are... ?
The debt collector.
I'm shutting down the Nursery.
I won't extend the repayment deadline.
Um... the caller from...
Working overtime?
No! I was hanging up posters for the bazaar and just lost track of time—
Oh no! You're a bad person; I won't tell you!
You're an interesting one, aren't you.
I thought so when I spoke with you on the phone too.
Did you tell Sayaka for me?
That I won't extend the repayment deadline.
Tell her that I came here today too, okay?
And that when the deadline comes, I'm destroying the Nursery.
You can't!
Even if there are still kids there.
So if you don't want anyone to get hurt, quickly get out of the way, yeah?
See you, Kobato.
I wonder if he was serious
about destroying the nursery...
And even if there are still children there... That's just terrible!
Even though he looks kind, there's something scary about him!
Who would "he" be?
Fujimoto!
Were you listening to me?
I couldn't help it. You were
speaking to yourself for so long.
I wasn't speaking to my—
What kind of guy was it?
I-I didn't ask him for his name...
He sort of smiled a lot and called Miss Sayaka "Sayaka" without any titles...
Okiura, huh?
Do you know him?
Did Miss Sayaka see him?
No...
He left after speaking to me.
Don't tell Miss Sayaka that he came here.
But...
It's fine, just don't say anything.
What'd you come there for?
If you make Miss Sayaka cry, I won't forgive you.
Got it? Don't you dare show your
face in front of Miss Sayaka again.
That man...
Hm?
He's named Okiura, isn't he?
I wonder how he's related to Miss Sayaka.
It's obvious, isn't it?!
Apparently Sayaka's been married before, and she shares the same last name as that guy.
He also just calls her Sayaka...
Then that person is Miss Sayaka's husband?!
Then why is he trying to shut down the nursery?
Don't get yourself too involved in this.
Huh?
More importantly, you have
something you need to do, don't you?
If you don't fill that bottle, you won't be
able to get to the place you want to go to.
But...
I'm worried.
So what have you been stitching over there?
A mascot!
I'm making it out of the cloth I got from Chitose!
Huh?
Is it a penguin?
It's a bunny...
Are those supposed to be ears?!
It doesn't matter what it is, penguin or otherwise!
I'll do my best in order to help make the bazaar successful!
You're gonna mass produce that mysterious lifeform?!
You sound like Fujimoto again! That's so mean!
Yomogi Nursery
Bazaar Site
It's rather bleak out today, huh.
It's okay.
Huh?
I'm sure it'll clear up.
That'd be nice.
Ioryogi?
I'll bring something that'll sell really well.
Thank you so much!
Let's do our best all day today!
Okay!
I'm sure the weather fortune dolls will bring good weather for us.
Yeah!
Kobato, no falling, okay?
Cause we're selling drinks and all, you know?
I won't!
You will.
I won't, I won't!
The two of you get along really well, don't you?
Not at all.
At all!
Hm?
You see those?
Fujimoto brought them here from his workplace.
Thank you...
There you go, falling.
I apologize...
Don't get too worked up.
Huh?
Ah! If I don't hurry up—
Kobato, you ended up falling after all.
HOT DOGS
YAKISOBA
The customers aren't coming, are they?
Even though we hung up posters and everything...
Don't worry! Your mothers might still be a little late, but I'm sure other customers will come soon!
Welcome
Weather Fortune Dolls
Really?
With things like this, maybe no one will come at all...
All because I said something like, "Let's have a bazaar"...
Hello!
Chitose!
I heard about the bazaar from Kobato and I've been looking forward to it!
Right?
Right!
Would you like some yakisoba?
Delicious Coffee
We have iced coffee too!
We can also make cafe au lait!
Thank you for coming!
I really have been looking forward to it. So have Chiho and Chise. But um...
When I looked around today, I noticed that all the posters had disappeared.
I was afraid this had been canceled.
What?
How could...
Don't tell me he...
Kobato?
I'm going to tell everyone that the bazaar hasn't been canceled!
Even if you go and tell them now—!
It's not too late!
They still might come!
Even if so, a little bazaar like this...
Even if it's just one more person, I still want them to come!
I mean... I mean, everyone's worked so hard for this!
Everyone, all of us together...
Kobato...
You feel the same way too, don't you, Fujimoto?
Kobato is a good girl, isn't she?
She really is.
Fujimoto?
She said she'd bring people, so at the very least I'll go and prepare coffee.
Not straightforward, but he's a good kid too, isn't he?
Yes, he is.
A chicken?
A sunfish?
DRINK STATION
They really aren't coming, are they?
Even though it's stopped raining and the sun's coming out...
DRINKS
Hello.
Is this the bazaar?
Y-Yes.
Kobato came and told me about it, you see.
I came to take a peek.
Am I at the right place?
I heard there was a bazaar.
I wonder if there are any treasures to be found?
Exciting!
Yeah. Where should we start from?
Welcome!
How much for yakisoba?
It's a success, isn't it?
Domoto...
Kobato told me about it.
Where is she? Has she not come back yet?
One iced coffee.
Right!
Mr. Kiyokazu, iced coffee!
Here you are.
See, there was this really energetic girl
running around shouting "Yomogi Nursery Bazaar!"
Bazaar!
She was so diligent, so I said, "Is that so? Maybe I'll stop by later!"
She took my hands and
pumped them up and down.
Thank you so much!
You can just see it, can't you? That's just like her.
Mommy!
Naomi! I'm sorry for being late.
There are lots of people here at the bazaar, aren't there?
Yeah!
It's great that the weather cleared up, huh?
Yomogi Nursery is having a bazaar!
Everyone, please come by!
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...Mysterious Lifeform, Part 2.